Megan and Amy are best friends. They share secrets. They chat with guys
online. And in a few days, they will never be seen again.
Megan Is Missing is a drama, horror, thriller film directed by Michael Goi.
Fourteen-year–old Megan and her best friend Amy spend a lot of time on the
internet, posting videos of themselves and chatting with guys online.
One night Megan chats with a guy named Josh who
convinces her to meet him for a date.
The next day, Megan is missing—forever.
Based on actual cases of child abduction.
Amy Herman, played by Amber Perkins.
Megan Stewart, played by Rachel Quinn.
Josh, played by Dean Waite.
Lexie, played by Jael Elizabeth Steinmeyer.
Kathy, played by Kara Wang.
Chelsea, played by Brittany Hingle.
Megan Is Missing is a 2011 American found footage psychological horror film
written, directed, edited, and co-produced by Michael Goi.
The film revolves around the days leading up to the disappearance of Megan Stewart (Rachel Quinn), a popular high school student in Los Angeles who decided to
meet up with a boy she was interacting with online, and the subsequent investigation launched by her best friend Amy Herman (Amber Perkins).
Goi based the film on a series of real-life cases of child abduction.
Marc Klaas, the founder of KlaasKids Foundation, notably endorsed the film.
Originally developed as a low-budget independent feature in
2006, the film was shot for $30,000–35,000.
It did not find distribution until Anchor Bay Films gave
it a limited theatrical release in 2011.
The film was very controversial upon its release.
Marketed as an educational film, Megan Is Missing was banned in New Zealand and has been heavily
criticized by critics for its depiction of sexual violence and brutal imagery.
Goi wrote the script in 10 days and shot the film over a week.
Because of the graphic content, he requested that the parents of the young cast be on set
during filming so that they were fully aware of their involvement in the project.
It is one of the first computer screen films.
The film experienced renewed popularity in 2020 after
clips of the film were shared on TikTok.
Goi later issued public warnings to prospective viewers after many users began calling the film "traumatizing." Entertainment Weekly called it
"2011's scariest horror film." The film placed sixth in the DEG Watched at Home Top 20 Chart for Week Ending November 21, 2020.
The film explores themes of rape, predator, based on
true story, murder, teenage girl.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.